♪ OH, OH, OH ♪
♪ YOU ARE MY EQUESTRIA GIRLS ♪
♪ I MET YOU
WHEN THE LIGHT SWITCHED ON ♪
♪ IT BRIGHTENS UP MY DAY
LIKE THE SUN ♪
♪ WHEN MY FRIENDS
COME A-RUNNIN' ♪
♪ YOU WERE RIGHT ALL ALONG
THAT TOGETHER ♪
♪ WE'RE ALWAYS BETTER ♪
♪ WE COULD TURN A SKETCH
INTO A MASTERPIECE ♪
♪ WHEN YOU'RE HERE,
I FEEL LIKE I'M COMPLETE ♪
♪ YOU ARE MY EQUESTRIA GIRLS ♪
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
CAPTIONS PAID FOR BY
DISCOVERY COMMUNICATIONS
♪♪
♪ BACK IN THE DAY ♪
♪ I USED TO WALK THESE HALLS ♪
♪ ACTING TOUGH, BUT ALL ALONE ♪
♪ I NEEDED A FRIEND ♪
♪ TO LEND ME A HELPING HAND ♪
♪ I COULDN'T DO IT ON MY OWN ♪
♪ WE'VE COME SO FAR TOGETHER ♪
♪ GOT MEMORIES TO TREASURE ♪
♪ I LOOK AT YOU,
STORIES COME BACK TO LIFE ♪
♪ AND IF I NEED REMINDING ♪
♪ I KNOW WHERE I CAN FIND YOU ♪
♪ IN THESE PAGES,
YOU'LL LAST FOREVER ♪
♪♪
♪ REMEMBER WHEN I ♪
♪ I LOST THE CROWN ♪
♪ YOU DIDN'T LEAVE ME ♪
♪ OUT IN THE RAIN ♪
WE STILL HAVE SONGS TO SING
♪ MAGIC TRANSFORMING ♪
♪ SPECIAL IN EVERY WAY ♪
♪ THE GEMS CHOSE US BY NAME ♪
♪ WE'VE COME SO FAR TOGETHER ♪
♪ GOT MEMORIES TO TREASURE ♪
♪ I LOOK AT YOU,
STORIES COME BACK TO LIFE ♪
♪ AND IF I NEED REMINDING ♪
♪ I KNOW WHERE I CAN FIND YOU ♪
♪ IN THESE PAGES,
YOU'LL LAST FOREVER ♪
♪ FOREVER ♪
AAH!
EXCUSE ME.
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T SEE YOU COME IN.
I'VE BEEN HERE
FOR A WHILE.
I DIDN'T REALIZE.
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO GET YOUR ATTENTION
FOR, LIKE, HALF THE SONG.
AIN'T SHE A QUIET ONE?
YEAH, AND WE KNOW
SOME PRETTY SHY PEOPLE.
AM I RIGHT?
WE DO, WHO?
I'M SUNSET SHIMMER,
PRESIDENT OF
THE YEARBOOK COMMITTEE
AND EDITOR-IN-CHIEF.
DO YOU WANT TO JOIN?
WE COULD ALWAYS USE
EXTRA HELP.
I'M WALLFLOWER BLUSH.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
I'VE BEEN ON
THE YEARBOOK COMMITTEE
ALL YEAR.
OH.
UH...
WE MET
IN NINTH-GRADE ENGLISH.
AND...I WAS SAYING...
IT WAS NICE
TO MEET YOU THEN.
YOU DIDN'T LET ME FINISH.
♪♪
ANYWAY,
I COUNTED UP ALL THE VOTES
FOR THE YEARBOOK
SUPERLATIVES.
[ ALL SQUEAL,
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
MOST LIKELY TO SUCCEED,
BEST SMILE, CLASS CLOWN...
[ GASPS ]
OH, WE WON BEST FRIENDS!
APPLEJACK, FLUTTERSHY,
RAINBOW DASH, RARITY,
PINKIE PIE, TWILIGHT SPARKLE,
AND ME.
I ALWAYS KNEW
I LIKED YOU ALL,
BUT NOW IT'S OFFICIAL
IN YEARBOOK FORM.
THE PEOPLE HAVE SPOKEN.
OH, GOOD FOR MICROCHIPS --
"MOST LIKELY TO INVENT
COLD FUSION."
NO REASON TO BE JEALOUS.
[ SCOFFS ] I'M NOT.
DON'T WORRY, TWILIGHT.
WE KNOW YOU'RE A GENIUS.
BESIDES,
IT'S JUST THE YEARBOOK.
[ ALL GASP ]
"JUST THE YEARBOOK"?
[ SIGHS ]
NOW YOU GONE AND DONE IT.
THE STUDENT BODY
HAS ENTRUSTED ME
WITH THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF GATHERING THEIR MEMORIES
INTO THE PAGES
OF THIS BOOK.
IN 30 YEARS, WE MIGHT NOT
REMEMBER EVERYTHING,
BUT WE WILL REMEMBER
WHAT'S IN THE YEARBOOK.
WELL, I'M ENTRUSTING YOU
NOT TO PUT US NEXT TO
"BEST MUSCLES."
EVERY TIME YOU CLOSE THE BOOK,
IT'LL BE LIKE
WE'RE KISSING BOTH BICEPS.
OH.
WHY DON'T WE TAKE OUR PICTURE
AT THE BEACH ON SATURDAY?
EVERYONE IS BOUND
TO LOOK ADORABLE.
BEACH DAY!
I'LL MAKE MY WORLD-FAMOUS
FUN-IN-THE-SUN CUPCAKES.
THE SECRET INGREDIENT
IS EDIBLE SUNSCREEN.
IT'S SPF FUN-HUNDRED.
YUCK.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
THE GREAT AND POWERFUL TRIXIE
DEMANDS TO SPEAK TO
THE YEARBOOK EDITOR IMMEDIATELY.
UNFORTUNATELY FOR ME,
THAT'S ME.
WHAT DO YOU WANT, TRIXIE?
[ GASPS ]
JUST AS I SUSPECTED.
I WAS NOT VOTED "GREATEST
AND MOST POWERFULEST."
EXPLAIN YOURSELF.
HOW SHOULD I PUT THIS?
YOU DIDN'T WIN
"GREATEST AND MOST POWERFUL"
BECAUSE IT WASN'T
ONE OF THE SUPERLATIVES.
HMM.
NEITHER WAS BIGGEST MEANIE,
BUT THAT DIDN'T STOP YOU
FROM WINNING IT
OUR FRESHMAN YEAR.
THAT WAS DIFFERENT.
THE WHOLE SCHOOL
VOTED FOR HER.
SHE WAS SO MEAN.
OF COURSE, WE ALL KNOW
YOU'VE EARNED THE RIGHT
NOT TO BE REMEMBERED
THAT WAY.
THANKS.
WE ARE NOT HAVING
A GREATEST AND POWERFULEST
SUPERLATIVE.
SORRY.
OH, YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'LL BE SORRY,
SUNSET SHIMMER.
WHEN YOU LEAST EXPECT IT,
I'LL HAVE MY REVENGE,
AND THEN I'LL DISAPPEAR
LIKE THIS.
BEHOLD,
THE MAGICIAN'S EXIT!
[ WHOOSHES ]
[ ALL COUGHING ]
[ DOORKNOB RATTLING ]
ALLOW ME.
WE WERE ACTUALLY
ON OUR WAY OUT.
♪♪
HMPH!
[ LAUGHTER ]
I'LL JUST FINISH UP...
OOP, FORGOT TO TURN OFF
THE LIGHTS.
...IN THE DARK.
Sunset:
DEAR PRINCESS TWILIGHT,
I THOUGHT YOU'D BE HAPPY TO HEAR
THAT THE GIRLS AND I
WERE VOTED BEST FRIENDS
IN THE YEARBOOK TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
IF YOU HADN'T FORGIVEN ME,
I'D STILL BE
THE ARROGANT STUDENT I WAS
WHEN I LEFT EQUESTRIA.
YOU GAVE ME THE SECOND CHANCE
I DIDN'T DESERVE,
AND I'LL NEVER FORGET IT.
YOUR FRIEND, SUNSET SHIMMER."
♪♪
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
GROUP PICTURE,
PRACTICE RUN NUMBER 36-A,
ATTEMPT SEVEN,
SUCCESS!
OH, NO.
[ GRUNTING ]
YOUR EYES
DO NOT DECEIVE YOU.
I FINALLY INVENTED
A SELFIE-SENSING CAMERA.
IT HOVERS INTO POSITION
WHENEVER IT DETECTS
A SELFIE OPPORTUNITY.
[ GRUNTS ]
I'D PREFER TO TAKE SELFIES
MYSELF-IE.
WHICH BEACH BLANKET
SHOULD WE USE
FOR THE PHOTOGRAPH?
YOU MEAN THE WHITE ONE
OR THE WHITE ONE?
[ SCOFFS ]
THIS IS TOASTED OAT,
AND LINEN LAMB'S WOOL,
EGGSHELL, WARM FROST,
PALE NIMBUS,
AND, WELL, THAT ONE IS WHITE,
I SUPPOSE.
YEAH.
THAT'S THE ONE
I WAS TALKING ABOUT.
[ WIND BLOWS ]
DON'T WORRY, RARITY.
I GOT IT.
♪♪
NO. I GOT IT.
I GOT IT.
NUH-UNH,
I GOT IT. I GOT IT.
OH!
I DON'T GOT IT.
[ GASPS ] OCEAN MONSTER!
Pinkie Pie:
OCEAN MONSTER!
QUINCY THE SEA TURTLE
SAYS THE TIDE'S COMING IN.
WE SHOULD
TAKE THE PICTURE SOON
OR RISK HAVING
DAMP ANKLES.
OH,
HE'S SO THOUGHTFUL.
ICK.
[ DRONE BEEPING ]
MWAH!
OH, TWILIGHT, YOU GOT
THE SELFIE SENSOR WORKING?
[ DRONE BEEPS ]
OKAY...
SO WHO'S READY TO TAKE
A BEST FRIENDS PICTURE?
UH-OH. WHAT DID I DO?
SHOULD WE DO IT NOW,
OR DID YOU WANT
TO SWIM FIRST?
HOW'S THE WATER?
SUNSET SHIMMER ASKING TO BE
IN OUR BEST FRIENDS PICTURE?
[ CHUCKLES ]
NOW I'VE HEARD IT ALL.
AM I MISSING THE JOKE
HERE?
Rarity: THE ONLY JOKE IS
WHATEVER THIS IS
YOU'RE PLAYING ON US,
ACTING ALL NICE
LIKE YOU'RE OUR FRIEND.
AND IT'S NOT FUNNY.
BECAUSE YOU AREN'T NICE.
AND WE AIN'T FRIENDS.
WAIT. WHAT?
YOU GOT APPLESAUCE
IN YOUR EARS?
I SAID, "WE AIN'T" --
WHOA!
♪♪
YOU SURE CAN.
I'M SO SORRY.
♪ MY FRIENDS ARE HERE
TO BRING ME AROUND ♪
♪♪
[ GASPS ]
IT'S LIKE
I'VE BEEN ERASED.
THIS HAS TO BE A BAD DREAM.
WAKE UP, SUNSET!
WAKE UP.
OW!
NOPE. YOU'RE AWAKE.
OW! [ LAUGHS ]
ME, TOO.
I CAN SEE YOUR MEMORIES,
AND I'M NOT IN THEM.
AND EXACTLY HOW IS IT
YOU CAN SEE OUR MEMORIES,
IF YOU DON'T MIND ME
ASKING?
WITH THIS.
[ SCOFFS ]
IT'S OBVIOUSLY
A CHEAP KNOCKOFF OF OURS.
WE GOT THEM TOGETHER.
YOU WERE THERE, REMEMBER?
WHY IS SHE STILL
TALKING TO US?
♪♪
PINKIE PIE, WHAT ABOUT
WHEN I CAME TO YOUR SLEEPOVER
BEFORE
THE BATTLE OF THE BANDS?
HAH! THE CLOSEST YOU'VE
EVER COME TO A PARTY OF MINE
IS FRESHMAN YEAR
WHEN YOU PRETENDED
TO BE APPLEJACK
AND TEXTED ME,
"YOUR PARTY IS LAMER THAN
A HUNGRY DUCK IN SNOW BOOTS."
LIKE I'D EVER SAY THAT.
IT REALLY
HURT MY FEELINGS.
AND WASN'T VERY NICE
TO THE DUCKS EITHER.
THAT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
TWILIGHT,
YOU REMEMBER ME, RIGHT?
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
SO MUCH TOGETHER.
PLEASE.
I ONLY MET YOU ONCE,
WHEN YOU YELLED AT ME
AT THE GAMES.
DOESN'T ANYONE REMEMBER
THAT I'VE CHANGED?
♪♪
MAYBE NOT ANY ONE.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
Rarity:
DON'T HURRY BACK, DARLING.
[ SIGHS ]
DEAR PRINCESS TWILIGHT,
THIS IS GONNA SOUND CRAZY,
BUT ARE WE FRIENDS?
AM I...NICE?
♪♪
PLEASE ANSWER."
[ TWINKLE ]
Princess Twilight:
OF COURSE WE'RE FRIENDS.
[ SIGHS HAPPILY ]
ARE YOU OKAY?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
KINDA HARD TO EXPLAIN.
MIGHT BE EASIER IN PERSON.
WELL, NOT PERSON,
SO TO SPEAK."
♪♪
[ ZAPPING ]
TWILIGHT!
SUNSET?
AAH!
OOPS. [ CHUCKLES ]
I WAS TRYING TO HUG YOU.
SO WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING?
THIS IS BAD, SUNSET.
IT'S WAY BEYOND ANYTHING
I'VE EVER HEARD OF,
ALTHOUGH...
WHAT?
I JUST HAD AN IDEA,
BUT YOU MIGHT NOT LIKE IT.
I'LL DO ANYTHING TO GET
MY FRIENDS BACK, TWILIGHT.
THERE IS ONE PONY
WHO MIGHT BE ABLE TO HELP,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU TWO
WANT TO SEE EACH OTHER.
WHO?
OH.
♪♪
Twilight:
SO, PRINCESS CELESTIA...
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
...YOU'LL NEVER GUESS
WHO'S BACK.
ACTUALLY,
MAYBE YOU CAN GUESS
'CAUSE SHE'S RIGHT HERE,
BUT, UM...
Am I helping?
[ SIGHS HEAVILY ]
PRINCESS CELESTIA,
THE LAST TIME WE SAW EACH OTHER,
I WAS
YOUR SNIDE LITTLE PUPIL
WHO BETRAYED
AND ABANDONED YOU.
I WOULDN'T HAVE SAID IT
THAT WAY.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
WHAT SUNSET MEANS TO SAY IS --
I MEAN THAT I COME BEFORE YOU
A CHANGED PONY,
HUMBLY ASKING FOR FORGIVENESS,
GUIDANCE, AND KNOWLEDGE.
OR I CAN JUST GO
AND YOU NEVER
HAVE TO SEE ME AGAIN.
I'VE MISSED YOU,
SUNSET SHIMMER.
♪♪
I'M SO SORRY.
EEE!
I AM NOT FAMILIAR
WITH THE EXACT SPELL
THAT COULD HAVE ERASED
YOUR FRIENDS' MEMORIES,
BUT IT SOUNDS LIKE
EQUESTRIAN MAGIC
IS AT WORK
IN YOUR WORLD.
HMM, INDEED.
THE TOILINGS OF THIS
NEFARIOUS ENCHANTMENT
COULD PORTEND
UNIMAGINABLE CATASTROPHE
IF LEFT UNCHECKED.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SORRY.
I'M JUST USED TO
HEARING YOU SAY,
"NO STUDENT PARKING
IN THE FACULTY LOT."
[ LAUGHS ]
THIS FACULTY LOT
YOU SPEAK OF
SOUNDS LIKE
A PLACE OF GREAT POWER.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
THE ANSWERS YOU SEEK
ARE IN
THE CANTERLOT LIBRARY.
♪♪
THERE'S OVER A MILLION BOOKS
IN HERE.
I WISH,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT SOMEPONY
WHO KNOWS THIS PLACE
LIKE THE BACK OF HER HOOF.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING,
PRINCESS CELESTIA?
TO THE RESTRICTED SECTION.
THERE'S A -- A RE--
A RE-- A RE--
BREATHE, TWILIGHT.
[ BREATHING SHALLOWLY ]
♪♪
[ BATS CHITTER ]
[ GASPS ]
OH, MY GOSH. OH, MY GOSH.
OH, MY GOSH.
SO MANY BOOKS, ALL UNREAD,
ANCIENT HISTORICAL
ARTIFACTS!
[ GASPS ]
I JUST -- I THOUGHT --
I CAN'T --
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
YOU SURE YOU'RE UP
FOR HELPING ME
GO THROUGH
ALL THIS STUFF?
DON'T TAKE THIS
AWAY FROM ME!
♪♪
NO WAY.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THEY HAVE
"CANTERLOT CANNIBALS,
VOLUME 31"?
YOU HEARD ME, 31!
SUNSET,
THAT'S WHEN IT GETS GOOD.
[ GASPS ] OVER HERE!
Twilight: WOULD YOU LOOK AT
THE WEATHER WARNING
FROM THE PRE-EQUESTRIAN
ERA!
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
OH, MY GOODNESS.
I CAN'T! I JUST CAN'T!
♪♪
[ YAWNS ]
DID YOU KNOW
CHANCELLOR PUDDINGHEAD
TRIED TO PASS A LAW
MANDATING EARTH PONIES
DRINK CARROT JUICE
AT EVERY MEAL?
I DO...KNOW THAT...NOW.
AW, SOUNDS LIKE YOU GOT TO READ
ALL THE FUN BOOKS.
[ YAWNS ]
I SHOULD PROBABLY
TAKE A BREAK FROM LOOKING.
[ YAWNS ]
BECAUSE I FOUND SOMETHING.
YOU'RE FAMILIAR WITH
"THE SEVEN TRIALS
OF CLOVER THE CLEVER"?
OBVIOUSLY, WHY?
WELL, FIRST OF ALL,
THESE DATE BACK TO BEFORE
THE FOUNDING OF EQUESTRIA.
LOOK AT THIS.
THE MEMORY STONE?
THAT SOUNDS PROMISING.
IT BELONGED
TO AN EVIL SORCERESS
WHO WAS PRACTICALLY
INVINCIBLE.
WITH THE MEMORY STONE,
SHE COULD ERASE ANY MEMORY
FROM ANYPONY,
EVEN FRAGMENTS
OF MEMORIES.
FRAGMENTS -- LIKE MEMORIES
OF ME BEING NICE?
MM-HMM.
CLOVER THE CLEVER KNEW
THE SORCERESS
HAD TO BE STOPPED
AND THE STONE DESTROYED,
SO HE CHASED HER
ACROSS LAND AND SEA.
BUT EVERY TIME HE GOT CLOSE,
THE SORCERESS WOULD ERASE
HIS MEMORY AND ESCAPE,
BUT HE KEPT FINDING HER.
HOW?
THESE SCRAPS OF PARCHMENT.
HE SECRETLY
WROTE EVERYTHING DOWN,
SO HE'D KNOW WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
AND WHERE TO GO NEXT,
LIKE A TRAIL
OF BREADCRUMBS.
CLEVER.
OH!
CLOVER THE --
YEAH. I GOT IT.
WHAT HAPPENED ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THIS PORTAL?
THE LAST PAGE IS MISSING.
CLOVER MUST HAVE HID IT
TO KEEP ANYPONY ELSE
FROM FINDING
THE MEMORY STONE.
SUNSET,
WHAT IF THE MEMORY STONE
ENDED UP IN YOUR WORLD?
AND SOMEONE IS USING IT
TO MAKE EVERYONE HATE ME AGAIN.
BUT WHO?
♪♪
A WHILE.
BUT WHO?
TIME TO REAPPLY.
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
SHOULD WE BE WORRIED
ABOUT SUNSET SHIMMER?
Trixie: YEAH,
WORRIED SHE COMES BACK.
I THINK IT'S A SHAME
THE WAY SHE'S TREATING YOU,
PRETENDING TO BE
YOUR FRIENDS.
SHE'S OBVIOUSLY
UP TO SOMETHING.
SUNSET THINKS
THE WHOLE SCHOOL EXISTS
JUST TO SERVE HER.
WATER, PLEASE.
♪♪
YOU KNOW, SEEING AS HOW
THE YEARBOOK PRESIDENT
SEEMS TO BE HAVING
A LITTLE IDENTITY CRISIS,
I BELIEVE THAT MEANS
THE VICE PRESIDENT TAKES OVER,
AND, WHY...[GASPS]
THAT'S YOU, RARITY.
IF THIS
IS YOUR WAY OF ASKING
TO BE MADE THE GREATEST
AND MOST POWERFUL,
THE ANSWER IS NO.
AND DIDN'T WE HAVE THIS
CONVERSATION YESTERDAY?
I CAN'T QUITE REMEMBER.
-UH...
-HMM.
MAYBE WE DID,
MAYBE WE DIDN'T.
MEMORY IS SUCH
A FICKLE THING.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN YOU'LL
FORGET SOMETHING IMPORTANT,
LIKE HOW GREAT
AND POWERFUL I AM,
WHICH IS WHY I NEED TO BE
IN THE YEARBOOK.
[ GROANS ]
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
THAT'S ALL I ASK.
♪♪
Sunset: I SHOULD BE GETTING
BACK TO MY WORLD.
MAYBE I CAN CONVINCE MY FRIENDS
I'M TELLING THE TRUTH
NOW THAT I KNOW
WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
Princess Twilight:
THE MEMORY STONE.
I'LL STAY HERE AND SEARCH
THE RESTRICTED SECTION
TOP TO BOTTOM
UNTIL I FIND A WAY TO GET
YOUR FRIENDS' MEMORIES BACK.
IF THAT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
OH, IT'S POSSIBLE,
EVEN IF HAVE TO REORGANIZE
THE WHOLE LIBRARY BY SUBJECT
OR MAYBE CHRONOLOGICALLY.
I'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
THANK YOU.
BOTH OF YOU.
THIS IS QUITE A CONTRAST
FROM THE LAST TIME
WE PARTED WAYS.
BUT YOU ARE NOT THAT WAY
ANYMORE.
WITH EVERY CHOICE YOU MAKE,
YOU PROVE YOURSELF
TO POSSESS A KIND HEART.
I GUESS
I HAD A GOOD TEACHER.
YOU WERE A GOOD STUDENT.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
ARE YOU SAYING I WASN'T
A GOOD TEACHER?
OH, NO. I WASN'T --
SHE DIDN'T SAY THAT.
-SHE DIDN'T SAY THAT, I --
-[ LAUGHS ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
PRINCESS CELESTIA
HAS A SENSE OF HUMOR?
LOOKS LIKE I'M NOT THE ONLY ONE
WHO'S CHANGED.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]]
[ DRONE WHIRRING ]
I'M NOT HOLDING BACK
THIS TIME.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M AFRAID OF.
BRING IT ON,
RAINBOW DASH.
YOU AND RARITY
JUST BOUGHT YOUR TEAM
A ONE-WAY TICKET
ON THE EXPRESS TRAIN
TO YOU'RE GOING DOWN.
OH, NICE GAME FACE,
PINKIE PIE.
THANKS.
I'VE BEEN PRACTICING ALL DAY.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT,
LITTLE BABY CAMERA?
YOU'RE IN MY HOUSE NOW!
[ DRONE BEEPING ]
Spike: [ BARKING ]
[ LAUGHS ]
SOMEBODY'S JEALOUS.
PLEASE.
CALL ME WHEN
THE FLYING CAN OPENER
LEARNS HOW TO FETCH.
YOU'RE THE WORST.
[ DRONE BEEPS ]
♪♪
[ MUNCHING ]
[ GROANS ]
Sunset: [ PANTING ]
GREAT NEWS, GUYS,
I'VE FIGURED IT OUT.
SOMEONE HAS ERASED YOUR MEMORY
WITH EQUESTRIAN MAGIC.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER,
BUT WE'RE STILL FRIENDS.
THIS IS THE MEMORY STONE.
DO YOU RECOGNIZE IT?
RIGHT, GUESS NOT,
BUT LOOK.
SEE? THIS IS PROOF.
WE ARE FRIENDS.
[ ALL MURMURING ]
Trixie: OH, PLEASE.
THIS IS THE SAME GIRL
WHO MADE FLAWLESS FAKE PHOTOS
OF YOUR FRIEND
TRASHING THE GYM.
YEAH. WAIT A MINUTE.
IS THIS SUPPOSED TO BE ME
MAKING SUCH
A RIDICULOUS FACE?
HA! I'D NEVER MAKE
A FACE LIKE THAT.
PREPOSTEROUS, FAKE I SAY!
[ LAUGHS ]
MY WORK HERE IS DONE.
TRIXIE OUT.
AND DON'T FORGET, RARITY,
YOU PROMISED TO PUT ME
IN THE YEARBOOK.
WAIT. YOU DID WHAT?
OHH!
[ CRASH ]
[ DRONE BEEPS SLOWLY ]
Twilight: [ GASPS ]
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I CAN HELP FIX IT.
I THINK YOU'VE HELPED
ENOUGH.
♪♪
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
I DON'T WANT
YOUR LUNCH MONEY.
I'M NOT MEAN, GOT IT?
I'M NOT MEAN!
♪♪
[ CLANGS ]
SO HERE WE ARE.
HERE WE DO ARE.
♪♪
YOU REALLY WANT TO DO THIS
HERE IN THE HALLWAY
IN FRONT OF EVERYONE?
UP TO YOU.
♪♪
BEHOLD,
COUNTERLOT HIGH SCHOOL'S
GREATEST
AND POWERFULEST STUDENT!
IF A SEVEN-SCALE MOCK-UP
DOESN'T CONVINCE YOU,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
WHERE'S THE MEMORY STONE?
YOU TURNED MY FRIENDS
AGAINST ME
JUST BECAUSE I WOULDN'T PUT YOU
IN THE YEARBOOK
AS THE GREATEST
AND POWERFULEST?
POWERFULEST
ISN'T EVEN A WORD!
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
IT'S NOT A WORD.
NO.
WHAT MEMORY STONE?
THE ONE YOU USED
TO ERASE EVERYONE'S MEMORY,
YOU MANIPULATIVE BLOWHARD.
A STONE THAT COULD MAKE
EVERYONE FORGET
ALL THE BAD TRICKS I'VE DONE,
WHICH IS NO TRICKS.
YOUR PUNY ROCK
PALES IN COMPARISON
TO THE GREAT AND POWERFUL
TRIXIE.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
I...DON'T.
SORRY.
[ GROANS ]
DID SOMEBODY REALLY ERASE
EVERYONE'S MEMORIES OF YOU?
MM-HMM.
AND EVEN THOUGH WE ALL KNOW
YOU'RE THE BIGGEST MEANIE,
YOU'RE SAYING
YOU'RE NOT MEAN ANYMORE.
IT'S COMPLICATED.
SO YOU HAVE THIS IDEA OF
WHO YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE,
BUT NO ONE AT SCHOOL
SEES YOU THAT WAY...
...IS THAT IT?
TRUST ME. I GET IT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I CAN'T BELIEVE THE ONLY PERSON
WHO BELIEVES ME
IS THE ONE I CALLED
A MANIPULATIVE BLOWHARD.
SORRY.
I TOOK IT
AS A COMPLIMENT.
LET ME HELP YOU
FIND THE STONE.
WHAT'S IN IT FOR YOU?
NO WAY.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
WELL, IF YOU'D RATHER GO ON
BEING THE BIGGEST MEANIE,
THAT'S FINE BY ME.
♪♪
I'VE LOOKED EVERYWHERE.
WHY CAN'T I FIND
THE MISSING PAGES?
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN GOOD TO YOU,
LIBRARY!
[ GASPS ] THIS IS IT.
THE LAST PIECE WAS
IN A SECRET COMPARTMENT.
CLOVER THE CLEVER
BURIED THE STONE!
THIS ROCK FORMATION MUST BE
SOMEWHERE IN THE OTHER WORLD,
BUT IT DOESN'T SAY
HOW TO GET YOUR MEMORIES BACK.
[ GASPS ]
"PERHAPS IF I HAD DESTROYED
THE STONE RIGHT AWAY,
SOME OF MY MEMORIES
COULD HAVE RETURNED,
BUT WHEN THE SUN SETS
BY THE THIRD DAY
AFTER A MEMORY
HAS BEEN TAKEN,
IT IS ERASED FOREVER."
YOU MUST WARN SUNSET SHIMMER
AT ONCE.
SO WHERE SHOULD WE START,
PARTNER?
HOW ABOUT WITH
WHAT I CALL YOU?
I'M THINKING, "THE GREAT
AND POWERFUL TRIXIE'S
PRETTY DECENT ASSISTANT
DETECTIVE HELPER PERSON."
♪♪
A CAFETERIA
FULL OF SUSPECTS,
TWO DETECTIVES
AND ONLY ONE MEMORY STONE.
SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE,
BUT SO DOES
PULLING A RABBIT OUT OF A HAT,
AND I DO THAT
ALL THE TIME.
LET'S TALK MOTIVE.
WHO HERE HATES YOU ENOUGH
TO ERASE EVERYONE'S
GOOD MEMORIES OF YOU?
IF YOU GO BACK
FAR ENOUGH...
EVERYONE. OH.
KNOWN ENEMIES, ALL.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
GOOD AFTERNOON, LADIES.
YOU FEELING OKAY?
THAT DEPENDS ON HOW WELL
YOU ANSWER MY QUESTIONS.
HAS ANYONE COME IN
COMPLAINING OF MEMORY PROBLEMS
IN THE LAST FEW WEEKS?
NOT THAT I CAN RECALL.
YOU CAN'T RECALL?
WE'RE TOO LATE.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU CAN TELL US ABOUT IT,
ANYTHING AT ALL?
I CAN'T TELL MUCH
FROM A DRAWING.
OKAY.
ONLY THAT IT'S
FELSIC INTRUSIVE IGNEOUS,
GRANULAR IN TEXTURE,
MOST LIKELY ARRANGED
IN AN EQUIGRANULAR MATRIX
WITH SCATTERED BIOTYPE MICA
AND AMPHIBOLE,
AT LEAST 65 PERCENT
ALKALI FELDSPAR BY VOLUME
WITH A MELTING POINT
OF 1250 CENTIGRADE
PLUS OR MINUS 10 DEGREES.
SORRY I COULDN'T BE
MORE HELPFUL.
SURE.
IT SEEMS LIKE WE'VE ONLY COME UP
WITH DEAD ENDS,
BUT, I MEAN,
IT COULD BE WORSE.
[ SIGHS ] IT'S WORSE.
GOOD AS NEW,
BEST FRIENDS YEARBOOK
GROUP PICTURE, TAKE TWO,
NUMBER 36-A,
ATTEMPT EIGHT.
♪♪
All: BEST FRIENDS!
OH, STOP LOOKING AT THAT.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA
WIND YOURSELF UP.
YOU CAN'T THINK
IF YOU'RE WOUND UP.
OH, THINK, TRIXIE!
I WANTED TO COME IN HERE
TO SEE WHO WE'RE MISSING,
BUT WE'VE TALKED TO EVERYONE,
A TO Z.
WAIT.
"NOT PICTURED,
WALLFLOWER BLUSH."
WHO'S WALLFLOWER?
I'M RIGHT HERE,
YOU KNOW?
WHO ARE YOU?
WALLFLOWER.
I'VE KNOWN YOU
SINCE THIRD GRADE.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
I REMEMBER THIRD GRADE,
NOT YOU SPECIFICALLY,
BUT WHAT A GRADE IT WAS.
THE GREAT AND POWERFUL TRIXIE
DEBUTED HER
DISAPPEARING FROG TRICK.
YOU KNOW,
A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T REALIZE
HOW MUCH WORK
GOES INTO RAISING TADPOLES.
YOU REALLY
HAVE TO CODDLE THEM.
Princess Twilight: SUNSET,
WE THINK THE MEMORY STONE
WAS BURIED
UNDER THIS ROCK FORMATION,
AND IF YOU DON'T
DESTROY THE MEMORY STONE
BY THE TIME THE SUN SETS TODAY,
ALL THOSE MEMORIES
WILL BE ERASED FOREVER.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO FIND
A ROCK FORMATION
THAT LOOKS LIKE
THAT ROCK FORMATION.
THAT'LL WORK.
CAN I ASK A SILLY QUESTION,
WALLFLOWER?
WHERE DID YOU TAKE
THAT LOVELY PHOTOGRAPH?
OH, THAT'S MY GARDEN.
WELL, THE SCHOOL'S GARDEN
TECHNICALLY.
I'M THE PRESIDENT
OF THE GARDENING CLUB.
I FOUNDED IT, TOO.
I'M ALSO THE ONLY MEMBER
AND THE ONLY ONE
WHO'S EVER BEEN TO THE GARDEN
OR SEEN IT
OR EVEN ASKED ABOUT IT.
YOU'RE NOT REALLY
INTO OTHER PEOPLE, HUH?
I WAS MAYBE
GOING TO ADD THIS PICTURE
SOMEWHERE
IN THE YEARBOOK.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
SORRY.
SUNSET DOESN'T LET ANYONE
PUT THINGS IN HER YEARBOOK
NO MATTER HOW MUCH
THEY DESERVE THEM.
NO.
YOU SHOULD DO THAT,
WALLFLOWER.
SO DON'T LET US KEEP YOU
FROM WORKING ON IT.
WHAT?
THE GREAT AND POWERFUL TRIXIE
IS ANNOYED AND INSULTED.
♪♪
WHAT ARE YOU --
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
♪♪
Applejack:
THAT WAS DIFFERENT.
THE WHOLE SCHOOL
VOTED FOR HER.
Pinkie Pie:
SHE WAS SO MEAN.
OF COURSE, WE ALL KNOW
YOU'VE EARNED THE RIGHT
NOT TO BE REMEMBERED
THAT WAY.
♪♪
[ SIGHS ]
WHY SHOULD YOU NOTICE ME.
AFTER ALL,
YOU'RE SUNSET SHIMMER.
EVERYBODY LOVES YOU, NOW.
WHY CAN'T THEY SEE
YOU HAVEN'T CHANGED?
♪♪
MM.
MM. [EXHALES SHARPLY]
[ CAT YOWLS ]
♪♪
YOU ERASED
EVERYONE'S MEMORIES?
UH...
YES.
WAIT.
WHO ARE YOU, AGAIN?
♪♪
♪ YOU DON'T SEE ME
FITTING IN ♪
♪ I'M SITTING HERE ALONE ♪
♪ RIGHT BESIDE MY SHADOW ♪
♪ ALWAYS ON MY OWN ♪
♪ IF I COULD SHARE
MY WILDEST DREAMS ♪
♪ MAYBE THEY WOULD SEE ♪
♪ I'M MORE THAN JUST
A WALLFLOWER ♪
♪ THERE'S SO MUCH MORE TO ME ♪
♪ I'M INVISIBLE, INVISIBLE ♪
♪ A DROPLET IN THE MIST ♪
♪ INVISIBLE, INVISIBLE ♪
♪ IT'S LIKE I DON'T EXIST ♪
♪ RIGHT BENEATH MY PICTURE ♪
♪ THIS IS WHAT YOU'LL READ ♪
♪ A LAUNDRY LIST OF NOTHINGS ♪
♪ NOT LIKELY TO SUCCEED ♪
♪ A YEARBOOK WITH BLANK PAGES ♪
♪ THAT NO ONE WANTS TO SIGN ♪
♪ A MEMORY FORGOTTEN ♪
♪ UNTIL THE END OF TIME ♪
HEY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
WHAT DID I DO TO YOU,
HONESTLY?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW YOU.
EXACTLY!
YOU HAD EVERYONE FOOLED,
BUT NOW THEY KNOW
YOU'RE STILL
THE BIGGEST MEANIE.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO SEE
HOW MEAN I CAN GET.
WHOA. WHOA. WHOA.
WHOA. WHOA.
LET'S NOT
ANTAGONIZE THE PERSON
WITH THE ALL-POWERFUL
MYSTERY ROCK.
I DON'T LIKE
CONFRONTATION.
LET'S JUST FORGET
THIS EVER HAPPENED.
DON'T ERASE --
WHAT WAS I SAYING?
I'M SURE IT WAS
SOMETHING BRILLIANT,
BUT ALSO,
HOW IS IT ALREADY 3:00?
WHY WON'T THIS DOOR OPEN,
AND WHAT ARE WE EVEN
DOING IN HERE?
I...DON'T...REMEMBER.
Sunset:
IS ANYBODY OUT THERE?
SOMEBODY, OPEN THE DOOR!
IF WE DON'T GET OUT OF HERE
AND FIGURE OUT
WHO HAS THE STONE,
IN A FEW HOURS,
IT'LL BE TOO LATE
TO RESTORE
EVERYONE'S MEMORIES.
I'LL LOSE MY FRIENDS
FOREVER.
HOW ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO CATCH SOMEONE
WHO CAN ERASE OUR MEMORY
EVERY TIME WE GET CLOSE
TO CATCHING THEM?
BY BEING CLEVER.
WHAT?
I WROTE MYSELF A NOTE.
"CHECK THE VIDEO."
YES.
IT'S BEEN RECORDING
THIS WHOLE TIME.
TWILIGHT'S CAMERA?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I DON'T REMEMBER DOING IT,
BUT I MUST HAVE REALIZED
OUR MEMORIES WOULD GET ERASED,
SO I PRESSED RECORD.
[ VIDEO REWINDING ]
[ BEEPS ]
THAT'S MY GARDEN.
WHO'S THAT?
WALLFLOWER BLUSH.
NAME'S NOT
RINGING A BELL.
Wallflower:
♪ YOU DON'T SEE ME FITTING IN ♪
UGH.
[ VIDEO FAST FORWARDS ]
LONG SONG, HUH?
Sunset: WHAT DID I DO TO YOU,
HONESTLY?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW YOU.
EXACTLY!
YOU HAD EVERYONE FOOLED,
BUT NOW THEY KNOW
YOU'RE STILL
THE BIGGEST MEANIE.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO SEE
HOW MEAN I CAN GET.
SHE'S KIND OF RIGHT
ABOUT YOU.
YEAH.
THANKS.
ACTUALLY, THE WISE
AND MORALIZING TRIXIE
WAS MAKING A POINT.
YOU SAID
YOU DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
I DIDN'T.
I WASN'T MEAN TO HER AT ALL.
BUT MAYBE IT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH
TO NOT BE MEAN TO SOMEONE.
MAYBE YOU HAVE TO BE NICE.
♪♪
YOU'RE RIGHT.
NOT THAT IT MATTERS,
I'M STILL TRAPPED IN HERE.
[ SIGHS ]
UNLESS YOU CAN MAGIC US
OUT OF HERE.
OH, WHAT'S THE POINT
IN TRYING?
YOU'VE SEEN ENOUGH OF MY TRICKS
TO KNOW WHAT'LL HAPPEN.
[ SIGHS ]
AT LEAST
WHEN THE SUN GOES DOWN
AND EVERYONE
HATES ME FOREVER,
I'LL STILL HAVE ONE FRIEND
IN THE MORNING.
HUH?
AND, I MEAN,
SHE IS THE GREATEST
AND POWERFULEST
CANTERLOT HIGH SCHOOL
HAS TO OFFER,
SO I GUESS
I CAN'T COMPLAIN.
YOU POOR FOOL!
YOU ACTUALLY BELIEVED ME
WHEN I WAS PRETENDING
TO GIVE UP?
MERE STAGE BANTER.
THE GREAT AND POWERFUL TRIXIE
NEVER GIVES UP ON HERSELF
OR HER FRIENDS.
I MEAN, HER PRETTY DECENT
ASSISTANT DETECTIVE
HELPER PEOPLE.
BEHOLD,
THE MAGICIAN'S EXIT.
YES! IT WORKED!
I FINALLY DID IT!
[ KNOCKS ON DOOR ]
STILL IN HERE.
UM... [ LAUGHS ]
UM, ALL PART OF THE TRICK.
HAVE YOU OUT IN A JIFFY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
JUST LEAVE ME IN HERE.
JUST GO.
I OWE YOU ONE, TRIXIE.
I WILL NEVER FORGET THIS.
NEVER SAY NEVER.
Sunset: WALLFLOWER?
♪♪
WALLFLOWER, STOP!
YOU REMEMBER MY NAME?
I REMEMBER EVERYTHING.
THE MEMORY STONE,
HOW I ACTED, ALL OF IT.
WHAT? HOW?
I ERASED
THE WHOLE AFTERNOON!
♪♪
LISTEN.
I USED TO BE JUST LIKE YOU.
SURE, I WAS POPULAR,
BUT I WAS LONELY.
YOU'RE NOTHING LIKE ME.
AND I'M NOT LONELY
BECAUSE I HAVE PLANTS.
THAT SOUNDED LESS LONELY
IN MY HEAD.
I'M SORRY, WALLFLOWER.
NO. YOU'RE NOT.
YOU'RE JUST TRYING
TO LOOK GOOD
IN FRONT OF YOUR FRIENDS,
AND IT'S WORKING.
GAH!
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO
GET BACK AT YOU
IF NOTHING I DO MATTERS?
I HATE YOU!
[ ALL GASP ]
I WANTED
TO TEACH YOU A LESSON
BY ERASING YOUR FRIENDS'
GOOD MEMORIES OF YOU,
BUT OBVIOUSLY
THAT DIDN'T WORK.
♪♪
WHAT IF I ERASED
ALL THEIR MEMORIES
OF HIGH SCHOOL?
YOU CAN'T.
YOU'D BE STEALING THEIR MEMORIES
OF EACH OTHER.
THEY'LL THINK OF EACH OTHER
THE WAY YOU THINK OF ME,
WHICH IS NOT AT ALL.
NO!
[ ALL GASP ]
I RUINED THEIR FRIENDSHIP
ONCE BEFORE.
I'D RATHER GIVE UP
MY OWN MEMORIES
THAN LET IT HAPPEN AGAIN.
FLUTTERSHY, NO!
APPLEJACK.
[GRUNTS]
RARITY.
AAH!
RAINBOW DASH!
PINKIE PIE!
[ GRUNTS ]
TWILIGHT,
DON'T FORGET ME.
♪♪
THIS ISN'T CANTERLOT.
WHERE AM I?
PRINCESS CELESTIA?
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO ME?
SOMEPONY HELP ME.
WHO ARE YOU?
WE'RE YOUR FRIENDS.
WE MAY NOT
REMEMBER YOU...
BUT AFTER SEEING
WHAT YOU DID...
THE SACRIFICE
YOU MADE FOR US...
WE'D BE PROUD
TO CALL YOU...
All: ...OUR FRIEND.
♪♪
[ TWINKLE! ]
[ GASPS ]
♪♪
WALLFLOWER, YOU HAVE MAGIC
YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND,
BUT IT IS NOTHING COMPARED
TO THE MAGIC OF --
YEAH. YEAH. WE GET IT.
LIGHT HER UP, LADIES!
TWILIGHT SPARKLE?
SUNSET SHIMMER.
♪♪
WE'RE SO SORRY.
I'M JUST GLAD
TO HAVE YOU ALL BACK.
I'M SO ASHAMED.
WHEN I FIRST FOUND
THE MEMORY STONE,
I ONLY ERASED
LITTLE THINGS --
AWKWARD HELLOS,
SAYING THE WRONG THING,
LITERALLY
ANY PUBLIC SPEAKING.
I'VE HAD PLENTY OF
AWKWARD MOMENTS
I WISH I COULD ERASE, TOO.
BUT IT'S NO EXCUSE.
I WAS SO USED TO
ERASING MEMORIES
THAT I GOT COMPLETELY
CARRIED AWAY.
I'M SORRY
FOR EVERYTHING.
IT'S OKAY.
I'M SORRY, TOO.
I MAY HAVE STOPPED
BEING MEAN,
BUT A GREAT AND POWERFUL FRIEND
HELPED ME REALIZE
I STILL WASN'T VERY NICE
TO YOU.
EVERYONE MATTERS,
WALLFLOWER,
NO MATTER HOW INSIGNIFICANT
OR INVISIBLE THEY FEEL.
♪♪
Sunset:
DEAR PRINCESS TWILIGHT,
YOU CAN ADD A NEW ENDING
TO THE ARCHIVES.
THE MEMORY STONE IS NO MORE.
Luna: NO STUDENT PARKING
IN THE FACULTY LOT.
♪♪
THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
GIVE MY BEST
TO PRINCESS LUNA
AND, OF COURSE,
THANK MY SECOND-BEST TEACHER,
PRINCESS CELESTIA.
MAKE SURE SHE KNOWS
YOU'RE KIDDING
WHEN YOU SAY THAT, THOUGH.
I'M HAPPY TO SAY EVERYTHING
IS BACK HOW IT USED TO BE.
I DEMAND TO SPEAK
TO THE YEARBOOK PRESIDENT!
HOW DID THIS
GET IN HERE?
♪♪
A YEARBOOK PRESIDENT
NEVER REVEALS HER SECRETS.
WELL, NOT EXACTLY
HOW IT USED TO BE.
I GOT A YEARBOOK DELIVERY
FOR BEST GARDENER.
♪♪
OH, COME ON!
SERIOUSLY?
♪♪