The last time I was here,
I woke them and ended up with a mane full of bats.
Thanks for being my basket holder, Spike.
Basket holder?
I thought I was your bodyguard!
What?
Yes, yes. That, of course, too.
For once I wish unicorn magic wasn't so…
luminescent.
Spike, you'll wake the bats!
Turn that off!
I can't!
I'm so glad you two could come.
Of course.
We so rarely get a chance to relax and just visit.
There is usually some crisis we have to deal with.
Somepony always needs our help.
But today
He-e-e-e-elp!
Twilight,
there's something wrong with Spike!
What's wrong?
I don't know.
All of the sudden my scales just started glowing and…
burning.
Little is known about the dragon culture.
But this is the phenomenon we've seen before.
It is the call of the Dragon Lord.
Dragons glow whenever the Dragon Lord
has need of them in the Dragon Lands.
Great.
How do I make it stop?
The only way to end the summons is to answer it.
You must journey to the Dragon Lands and see what is expected of you.
B-but the Dragon Lands is full of…
dragons!
And they're ghastly creatures.
Oh, oh, not you, of course, Spikey-Wikey.
But remember that rotten Garble?
How could I forget?
He would've burnt us to the crisp if you weren't there.
If I have to go to dragon lands,
would you two come with me?
Oh my goodness, I'd love to!
We're sadly lacking any information about dragon culture and customs.
I could research them. Maybe even write an article!
This could be my chance to make great contribution to the knowledge of Equestria!
And be there for Spike, of course.
Be very careful.
The Dragon Lands are particularly dangerous for ponies.
It would be wise to be discreet.
I'm sure I still have the dragon costume
we used the last time we snuck into Dragon Lands.
I think we might want something a little more… practical this time.
Well, it might be practical,
but this disguise isn't flattering in the slightest.
It's not supposed to be flattering, it's supposed to blend in.
Hey, hey, look!
It's our old friend Sparkle-Warkle!
It's Spike.
Are you sure your pony friends didn't give you a pony name?
It's nice to see you too, Garble.
I didn't say it was nice to see you.
It's not.
I don't like you.
Wasn't I clear about that?
Hey! That's my rock!
Oh, really?
Then why aren't you sitting on it?
Dragons of Equestria!
HEAR ME!
I have been Dragon Lord for longer
than many of you can remember.
And my reign has been extraordinary.
AGREE WITH ME!
Torch! Torch! Torch! Torch!
Who is that?
It's Dragon Lord Torch, dummy.
No, next to him.
That's daughter, princess Ember.
I wouldn't even look at her if I were you.
Unless you want Torch to eat you.
This is fascinating!
Dragons are notoriously reckless,
but they do whatever their Dragon Lord says!
Unfortunately,
according to dragon law,
it is time for me to step down.
Sad, I know.
BE SAD!
This is why I have summoned you.
To compete for the throne in a Gauntlet of Fire.
Whomever has the strength and fortitude
to retrieve this Bloodstone Scepter from the heart of the flamecano
will be crowned Lord of the Dragons!
When the Scepter disappeared,
the dragons stopped glowing!
We are learning so much!
Excuse me.
You even sneeze like a pony.
The Gauntlet is dangerous.
For I designed it myself.
Only dragons with my ferocity, strength, and determination
will be able to finish.
We will gather at the cliff
when the sun is at it's peak!
I don't want to be Dragon Lord or dragon toast,
and I stopped glowing, so let's sneak out of here!
Where do you think you are going, little dragon?
Oh, hi, Your Lordship.
I was just going home.
You don't get to leave unless I say you can!
Dad, look at him. He's just a runt.
Besides, he does not even want to compete.
Let him go.
He is rather tiny.
I could squish him with my pinky claw.
That wasn't a joke, it was a fact.
When I want you to laugh I will say: "Be amused!"
Of course, Your Lordship.
I guess I don't understand dragon customs.
Another reason why I shouldn't compete.
Very well, little dragon.
I release you.
Thank you. And thank you.
Where do you think you are going?
To prepare for the Gauntlet.
No, you are not.
You are not much bigger than that runt I just sent home.
But, I'm smarter than most of these boulderheads
and you know it!
Being smart won't help you win this Gauntlet.
It was designed for a big strong dragon to win.
Because it takes a big strong dragon to live.
Besides,
I said NO!
I hate when he does that!
When I become Dragon Lord,
I will make burps an official greeting!
You? Please.
When I win I will pillage Equestria for all their pillows.
Why should these ponies live be comfortable while we sleep on rocks?
That's nothing.
When I'm in charge,
the first thing I'll do is get revenge on these puny ponies!
They'll regret they ever crossed Garble!
We'll take whatever we want from Equestria and burn the rest!
Oh my gosh.
I can't believe I'm saying this,
but I hope that burping dragon wins.
None of them can win.
Equestria is in big trouble if any of them are in charge.
But what can we do?
There is only one thing to do, and only I can do it.
I have to win the Gauntlet of fire!
What do you mean you have to win the Gauntlet?
It's the only way to protect Equestria from the dragons
You heard them.
They have horrible plans for ponies if they win.
So somehow, I have to do it.
There has to be another way.
It's too dangerous.
Besides, if you win, you'd have to stay here.
I know.
But there's no other way to keep my friends safe.
Well, if you're staying to compete,
then we're staying to cheer you on.
I thought I released you, tiny one.
I decided to compete.
I am a dragon after all.
Are you sure?
You can't even fly.
All dragons are welcome to compete,
But they do so at their own peril.
Flying to flamecano island is the first of many challenges you will face
in your quest to find The Bloodstone Scepter
Good luck!
Just kidding, i hope you loose.
Thanks Garble,
I was planning on swimming anyway.
You can do it, Spike.
He is gonna drown!
Spike!
Hey, are you okay?
Princess Ember?
What do you think you're doing?
Only saving your ungrateful scales.
Did that Seaweed just talk?
Ponies?
What are they doing here?
They're my friends.
Friends?
Dragons don't do friends.
Well, this dragon does.
Whatever.
I don't care as long as none of you get in my way.
I have a Gauntlet to win.
But I thought your dad said…
I don't care what my dad said!
I'll show him and every dragon who thinks I'm just some little princess,
there are better things than being big and strong.
Don't leave me here, Spike.
Knew you'd do it.
Your pony friends made you soft.
You're welcome.
For what?
I didn't say thank you.
Wow.
You even smell like ponies.
Or is it coming from over there?
Uh, that's just me.
I, uh, robbed some ponies on my way over here.
I like your style.
Have I met you before?
You kind of look like…
My, uh, old neighbor,
Sandy…
Rockbeach.
Stupid slingtails knocked me down.
But I've wasted enough time making small talk…
Get it?
Because you're too small to win this!
I'm funny.
Why did you cover for me?
You could've have had one less competitor.
I could ask you the same thing.
You could've told Garble about my friends.
That looks rough.
But that's would makes it a challenge.
Are you kidding?
Those boulders are huge!
Hey, what if we work together?
You'll fly me up there and I'll help to look out for boulders.
Like a second set of eyes.
Spike!
Are you sure it's a good idea to team up with Ember?
You don't know her too well.
I do know she could have told Garble about you, but she didn't.
I think we can trust her.
Her behavior does seem contradictory to everything I've noted about dragons so far.
Hey, you, little fellow!
I thought about it. And the plan makes sense.
Let's do it.
Really?
Great! It's a deal.
Just so you know,
this doesn't mean we're gonna pick flowers or exchange necklaces
or whatever pony-friends do.
Good luck. We'll meet you at the top.
Pull up, there's one on your tail!
Go left!
So what do we do now?
I think we go through there.
Oh, that looks scary.
I mean… You can do it!
Listen, Spike.
I wouldn't have made it so far without you.
So, I guess, if you want to, we could keep working together.
I mean, just until I get through the tunnel.
Okay!
We'll be right behind you.
You made it!
Oh, we were so worried.
About us?
That tunnel was cake.
Wait. How did you two get through?
Rarity!
Thanks, Spike!
It was nothing.
Nothing?
You just risked everything to save her.
And they're putting themselves in danger just to support you.
Well, that's just what friends do.
Don't you have anyone who looks out for you?
Not really.
Unless I count you.
Which I don't, because we were only
helping each other get through the tunnel.
And now we're through the tunnel, so…
that's it.
Wait, what do you mean?
Well, there's only one winner,
one Scepter, and one Dragon Lord.
So I guess it's every dragon for themselves.
So we aren't really friends?
Maybe if we were in pony land, but…
Like I said, dragons don't do friendship.
I can't believe Ember ditched me.
Oh, you're better off.
She was only looking out for herself.
She's just like all the other dragons.
She's not though, I know it!
She saved me even when she didn't have to.
I don't care what she says,
that makes us friends.
Is it just me or we've seen this crevice three times already?
That's kinda hard to tell, huh.
They all look the same…
except for this one, look!
We made it!
I can't believe I'm the only dragon to make it this far.
You're not!
And I'm not losing to the puny pony-loving dragon like you!
We have to do something!
Look!
Ember!
I thought it was every dragon for themselves.
Why did you saved me?
That's what friends do. And I am… I mean we are.
I never should have left you back there.
Please don't make me talk about my feelings.
What the?..
Spike! Get the Scepter!
I'm sick and tired of you two helping each other!
Dragons don't do helping!
These dragons do!
Leave her alone!
What? You! You have the Scepter?
But that means that you are…
The Dragon Lord!
Dragon Lord Spike.
That's right!
Now go start your long journey home.
And give every dragon you see on your way a hug.
Don't tell them why.
But that would be super embarassing.
I command you to do it!
I can't believe this.
Dragon Lord Spike.
Has a nice ring to it.
"Dragon Lord Ember" sounds a lot better.
What? No. You are the Dragon Lord now.
The Dragon Lord is whoever brings the Scepter back to your father.
Besides, you'll make a great leader.
I was just doing this to protect the ponies.
But I know you'll protect them just as well as I would have.
You sure about this?
Absolutely. My home is in Equestria with my friends.
Well, you'll have at least one friend here too.
What are you doing?
It's called "a hug".
Oh. I don't know if I like it, but okay.
Ember? You?
I know you didn't think I can do it, but I did.
I expressly told you not to do it, because you're not—
I'm not big and strong, I know.
But you know what? I won anyway.
So maybe it takes more than just being big and strong
to be a good Dragon Lord.
I was wrong, Ember.
You might not be big.
But you are strong. And smart.
And perhaps that counts for more than I thought.
And you will make an excellent leader.
Thanks, dad.
AGREE WITH HIM!
Just kidding. That's not gonna be my thing.
Dragons! Hear me!
I present to you a new Dragonlord
Ember!
What is the meaning of this?
I can't tell you.
You did well, Spike.
With Ember as Dragon Lord the ponies will be safe,
and you've gained us a powerful ally.
And a new friend!
Plus, Ember said I could write to her any time I had questions about dragon culture!
With this much information,
I'll be able to write a whole book on dragons!
And I gained tons of ideas for a new line of camouflage clothing!
I think I'll call it… "Camo Mode".
СЧАСТЛИВЫЙ ПОНЕЦ
anon2anon
sunnysubs.com