I wish the mailpony would just come already!
I can't wait another minute to find out if Rainbow Dash got in or not!
Pinkie Pie, you're more nervous than Rainbow Dash!
I'm not nervous at all!
When I get into the Wonderbolt Academy…
If you get in!
IF you get in!
Don't jinx it!
I'm telling you, it's in the bag!
She is the best flyer in Ponyville.
In Ponyville?
I'm probably the best flier in all of Equestria.
I wouldn't be surprised if they just went ahead
and made me a Wonderbolt on the first day.
Got a letter here for Rainbow Dash.
I didn't get in.
Gotcha!
You guys are so gullible.
Like I wasn't gonna get in!
I'm just sooooooooooo happy for you!
Thanks…
Pinkie Pie…
I kinda need to get going.
Okay. I'm done!
The sooner I get there, the sooner I get to show them my stuff!
See you guys in a week!
Good luck!
Won't need it!
DON'T FORGET TO WRITE!
Do you think she heard me?
Oh yeah! This is gonna be sweet!
Well lookie what we got here.
Bet y'all think you're Wonderbolt material, don't ya?
Yes ma'am!
Think you got what it takes to be an elite flyer?
Well then. Let me be the first to tell you.
YOU DON'T!
If you had what it took to be an elite flyer,
you'd already be a Wonderbolt!
Still think you're something special?
No ma'am!
Ya think you're hot stuff?
You look like you're the worst flyer in the whole academy!
You'll probably quit after the first day!
No ma'am! I'd never quit, ma'am!
What about you?
Bet you couldn't fly past the first flagpole without getting winded.
Try me, ma'am.
What's that?
Let me show you what I've got, ma'am.
You want a chance to prove yourself, huh?
Yes ma'am!
Well then, now's your chance.
Give me five hundred laps!
All of you!
NOW!
Lap four-hundred and ninety-nine!
One more lap to go!
You're on!
Five hundred!
Not bad!
For a couple of newbies…
Name's Lightning Dust.
Rainbow Dash!
Wanna grab some grub in the mess hall?
Definitely.
Pinkie Pie, Rainbow Dash hasn't even been gone twenty-four hours yet.
Give her a chance to settle in first.
Why don't we just go see what Twilight's up to?
I hear Princess Celestia's got her working on some new spells!
New spells, huh?
Okay!
Wait!
If I'm not here when Rainbow Dash's letter arrives,
I won't be able to read it right away.
And if I don't read it right away, I won't be able to write her back right away.
And if I don't write her back right away, she might think I didn't get her letter
and then she might worry it got lost
and if she's worried about her letter she'll get distracted,
and if she's distracted then she won't do well at the academy,
and if she doesn't do well at the academy, then she'll get kicked out
and if she gets kicked out, she'll never be allowed to be a Wonderbolt,
and if she doesn't get to be a Wonderbolt, all her dreams will be crushed!
And it will be all…
my…
FAULT!
So in other words, you're stickin' by the mailbox.
Yep!
Suit yourself.
The Wonderbolts are the fastest, best precision flyers in the world.
But spinouts can still happen.
And when they do, a Wonderbolt must be able to recover quickly.
This…
is the Dizzitron.
It's gonna make you very, I repeat, very dizzy.
Your task is to try and recover, and fly straight again.
As soon as possible.
Once you have recovered you must come in for a smooth landing.
Now, who's first?
You.
You're up.
Me?
NOW!
Ready?
Yes ma'am!
Go!
Release!
Fifteen seconds. Decent.
But I wouldn't go writin' home about it! Who's next?
All right, Rainbow Dash. Let's see what you got.
Yes ma'am!
Okay, go!
Release!
Six seconds?!
That's an academy record.
You made it look so easy.
I make everything look easy.
Okay Lightning Dust, you're up.
Ma'am, can you put the Dizzitron at maximum speed?
I wanna push my limits.
You sure about that?
Yes ma'am.
Okay. You asked for it.
Release!
Six point five seconds.
Not bad.
NEXT!
No pony even came close to six seconds!
They should make us Wonderbolts right now!
Yeah they should!
Listen up!
For the rest of the camp, you'll be working in pairs.
'Morrow morning I'll post the teams including who'll be lead pony,
and who'll be wing pony.
Good luck.
Like we're going to need it!
Heh, yeah!
So, which one of you lucky gals gets to be my wing pony?
What?
You might want to check the wall.
A wing pony?
They made us a team! Isn't that awesome?
Permission to enter, ma'am.
What is it Rainbow Dash?
I had the best time on the Dizzitron! Only six seconds!
And?
And you made me a wing pony!
Because I believe you and Lightning Dust will be an unstoppable team.
Do you not think you'll be an unstoppable team?
Yes ma'am!
I mean, no ma'am! I mean…
We'll be an unstoppable team, ma'am.
Then what's the problem?
I think I should be lead pony, ma'am.
And I think Lightning Dust likes to push herself a little harder than you do.
That's why I made her lead pony. Got it?
Yes ma'am.
Good.
Today you will all be participating in the flag hunt.
We'll divide you into two teams.
Red,
and blue.
Whoever finds the most flags of the opposing team's color wins.
Oh, this is gonna be so much fun!
If you think this is going to be fun, you are sadly mistaken.
This is for training purposes.
This is not recess.
Lead ponies and wing ponies must fly together.
If any pair splits apart, they will be immediately disqualified.
Do you understand?
Yes ma'am!
Then let's go!
Ready to rock and roll?
Ready.
You spotted any flags yet?
Not yet.
Oh! There's one!
Good eye!
We should slow down.
It doesn't look like both of us can make it at this speed!
Lightning Dust and Rainbow Dash found the first flag!
Come on! Let's find some more!
Sure. Just give me a second.
Oh, you're fine.
Yeah… totally.
She's still at it.
I just wish we could help her!
Help me? The only thing that could possibly help me is a letter from Rainbow Dash!
It's been three days already.
By now, she probably doesn't even know our names anymore!
She probably can't remember our faces!
"Pinkie Pie? I never heard of a Pinkie Pie! Who is Pinkie Pie?"
Well if you're so worried, then why don't you send her a letter first?
Of course! That's a great idea!
Oh wait! I got an even better idea!
How about we send Rainbow Dash a care package?
You know, before she forgets all about us?
Although, come on, let's face it. It's probably too late for that.
But uh, maybe it'll jog her memory somehow!
Pinkie Pie, I'm sure Rainbow Dash still remembers our faces and who we are.
But I think sending her a care package is a great idea!
A care package it is! We'll send it through the mail!
WAIT! Ah! That won't work at all!
Why not?
Because what if the package gets lost in the mail?
What if somepony else gets the package by accident
and then she remembers us instead of Rainbow Dash
and she becomes our new friend,
and then the real Rainbow Dash wouldn't ever know that she used to have friends and she forgot them!
Is anypony else following this?
I've got it!
We'll deliver the care package to Rainbow Dash in person!
I wouldn't mind a little trip.
I'll go!
Count me in!
Me too.
Me five!
But don't be upset if she doesn't recognize you at first.
It may take a while for her to get her memory back.
Today we'll be doing our famous air obstacle course.
The object of this exercise is to work on your precision flying under extreme circumstances.
And don't worry about winning.
It's not a race.
Now everypony, get on your marks!
Can't they go any faster?
It's no good, I can't get around them!
It doesn't matter!
We can still fly completely in sync and blow Spitfire's mind with our moves!
I guess…
What are they, a couple of snails?
It's just a little weather.
Now's our chance to pass these slowpokes!
Not bad!
And in record time, too!
Definitely made the right decision making you two a team.
The others seem to have had a little trouble with the precision part of the exercise.
I'd better go help sort them out.
Why don't you two go hit the mess hall early?
Yes ma'am!
Thank you ma'am!
Lightning Dust?
Next time, maybe we don't cut the other teams off like that?
Hey, you snooze, you lose!
Besides, Wonderbolts are supposed to be able to recover from a spinout.
You saw them on the Dizzitron!
They could use the practice.
I mean, it's not our fault we're so much better than those other guys!
Not every pony is destined to become a Wonderbolt.
Only the best of the best, right?
Yeah, I guess you're right…
'Course I'm right!
Now let's go fuel up! Kicking all that tail has made me hungry.
Yeah!
I have an idea about how we can literally blow away our competition.
But we're already way ahead.
Are you in, or not?
Lightning Dust likes to push herself a little harder than you do.
That's why I made her lead pony.
I'm in!
Then follow my lead!
I can't control it!
It's a twister!
Hold on!
Noooooo!!
Are you guys okay?
Pinkie Pie!
You… remember me!
Well yeah, of course I remember you! But what are you all doing here?
We wanted to bring you a care package.
Didn't realize you'd be in the middle of some crazy tornado drill.
That… was… Awesome!
Awesome?
My friends could have been smashed to pieces!
Yeah, but they weren't, right?
Can't say the same for the clouds.
We totally wiped them out with that tornado.
The other cadets will have to be up there for days to bust as many as we did.
A hoof bump? Seriously?
You made me clip my wing.
You sent half of our class into serious tail spins on the obstacle course.
You unleashed a tornado that nearly demolished my friends!
Yeah. And?
And I get that you want to be the best.
So do I!
But you're going about it in the wrong way.
The Wonderbolts don't seem to think so.
After all, Spitfire did make me the leader and you the wing pony and you the wing pony.
You're right.
She did.
This better be important.
You're supposed to be up there busting clouds with your partner.
We're done with that, ma'am.
Already? That's an academy record!
Explain your methods.
That's why I'm here ma'am.
Lightning Dust decided to use a tornado.
A bit excessive for cloud-busting.
But judging from your time, it was obviously an effective tactic.
Yeah, well that "effective tactic" nearly took out my friends!
No disrespect ma'am,
but there's a big difference between pushing yourself has hard as you can,
and just being reckless.
And if being reckless is what gets rewarded around here,
if that's what it means to be a Wonderbolt, then I don't want any part of it.
What are you saying, newbie?
I quit.
You did what?
Being a Wonderbolt was your dream!
Not anymore.
I'm sorry, Rainbow Dash.
I know how much this meant to you.
Rainbow Dash!
How dare you storm out of my office without giving me a chance to respond!
The Wonderbolts are looking for the best flyers in Equestria.
You were right. Being the best should never come at the expense of our fellow ponies.
It's not just about pushing ourselves.
It's about pushing ourselves in the right direction.
You've shown that you're capable of doing just that.
You're no wing pony, Rainbow Dash,
you're a leader.
Now get out there and give me twenty!
Yes ma'am!
Wait!
You didn't even get to open your care package!
SCHASTLIVIY PONETS
anon2anon
sunnysubs.com